welcome back
today we are going to work on the Infinity infrastructure required to enter the UEV tier
completing the Relative Quest was easy
but I think we are still not ready for the next tier
there are a lot of things we should fix in our base before going on
starting from our lack of fuel
after fixing that
ae2 still doesn't have enough power for high speed item transfers
but instead of a better power plug
I think it's time to craft the neutronium energy cell
and that reminded us that we should probably fix our AE2 cable mess
if that looked clean
it is only because that was the peer to peer network
we can't really fix that
but we can make it more manageable
messing with that controller could halt our whole base
so we shall build a new one
the issue is that
if we were to use wireless cables like that
we would waste about half of the connections we can have
so we will still have peer to peer connections
however
instead of managing those with cables and a huge subnetwork
we just bring those where we have enough space to build a wall of wireless connectors
and there we have the first half of our poorly designed new controller
not only it's not the optimal Hilbert curve version
it also has a whole wasting 900 channels
anyways
we now have a nice wall of wireless connectors ready for use
to which we have to reconnect our whole base
each peer to peer segment we had one by one
and we are going to remove as many cables as possible
since those increase the game loading time
after reconnecting everything to the new controller
we can check how much of a mess it looks like
and the power usage seems to not even reach 1 ZPM amp
we didn't even need the neutronium energy cell
the next thing we are going to need is more circuits
and it looks like our vats can't produce
also
we can switch to a recipe that has 8 times more yield
however
that requires a bacteria which is rather hard to get
it takes 3 minutes with a 7% success rate
but we had 8 labs running that stuff for the whole last episode
so we got our back covered
by the way
there was a better way to duplicate bacteria cultures
but we are lazy
now we just have to build a new set of vats
stuff some of the fluid we already have in the output to kick start it
and we are done
however
we also want faster circuits
so we built some more assembly lines
luckily
we can now copy the input bus settings with a data orb
and then we just expand the input sub network
since we can now mass produce bio circuits
we shall also review what kind of circuit we use for each tier
making bio stuff with that recipe used quite some infinity
and we run out of it
so we made three more space mining modules
with a filter to only gather that stuff
to provide the computation
instead of making three more computers
we expanded the old one
and added a network switch
to split the computation between the six mining modules
and of course
our ore processing plant couldn't keep up with a single mining module
so we overclocked it further
and we added a bunch more
crafting all of that stuff clogged our extruder and our wire mill
but instead of improving our extruding capacity
we instead worked on a proper component assembly line
this will save materials
and skip most of the extruding part
also doing this will free a lot of space from our general purpose assembly lines
that machine looks really cool
but we will make it vertical to fit a single chunk
but this machine could not keep up with our needs
so we overclocked it a bit more
just to the point where it uses as much as one of our blast furnaces
speaking of which
after fixing the pollution issue once for all
we shall also upgrade
once we have enough to match our power generation
we notice that our battery won't act as a buffer any more than the laser connectors do
so after getting a CPU with 160 million capacity and 8,000 cores
we start working on a better battery
crafting such a thing will take a lot of time
but instead of waiting
we can use that time to improve our base
the first thing that got clogged was our mixer
so we started working on some extra mixers that will share the same inputs
and we pushed those a little bit more
next our EBFs stopped working due to lack of oganesson
so we built a couple more matter fabricators
and only after the build was complete
we realized that
we could have pushed for a double overvolt
or maybe we should have added even more energy hatches
we should do more testing next time
the next thing we notice is that our cable covering machine is slow
this machine for sure does not lack speed
what it lacks of is polyphenylene sulfide sheets
those are passively produced by one of our oldest chemical reactors
which is still running in HV
luckily we had a ZPM cable close by
which can make it go 200 times faster
the next bottleneck is Electrum
here the issue is the speed at which we send it to the furnace
1000 items buffer is simply too small
so we upgrade to an input crafting buffer
and by the time we complete the operation
we can already see how many items has been queued up inside it
but it shouldn't take too much to complete the task for our current furnace
the next bottleneck is the bending machine
which has the same issue
and it was also having issues with the output
that is due to the buffer limitation of the bus
which can be increased with a storage cell
now it can unleash its true potential
the next thing we notice is crystal SoC
we used to make those with a lot of emeralds in a convoluted way
but we can now switch to a better recipe
and we can fix that with our wireless terminal
but after modifying a pattern
we must also restart the crafting
the next thing we notice is that
we are making no progress with circuits
that is due to lack of circuit boards
after inspecting our PCB factories
we remember that we do not have the perfect overclock upgrade
and that nanites will make those work 10 times faster at best
so we change plan
and revert back to using LCR
but that requires a lot of extra acids
those are passively made
and the issue here is about the amount we are stocking
so we increase the size of the tank
however filling it will take some time
due to the many steps required for that fluid
so since that is required for the thousands of HV circuits
we can instead do a manual batch of a different circuit that does not use epoxy
and we right away notice the speed at which we make the plastic bars
that was an almost unused recipe
so it was left inside the old HV Fluid solidifier
thanks to our wireless universal terminal
we can quickly multiply the pattern
and move it to the bigger solidifier
and with that
we have completed our batch of surrogate circuits
but we have to convert those into the generic version
possibly without editing patterns
so we add a stocking bus on our press
once we get back to our battery
we notice that our laser and our cutting machines are not working
that is due to lack of extreme temperature treated water
the issue here was the production speed
so we increased the parallel count
and that made the machine need a little bit more of power
so we started using lasers there too
but our cutting machine still didn't cut it
so we started working on an ugly convoluted mess to help it
and finally we completed our new battery
to use it
we have to put it in a box
and place it inside our battery multi block
that new battery has quite some capacity
and with our current power production
filling it up will take a couple of years
so what did we learn today
yeah
let's not spend too much time trying to craft some weird ancient device
欢迎回来！
今天我们将建设进入UEV所需的无尽基础
完成对应的任务很容易
但我想我们还没准备好进入UEV
在继续之前
基地仍有许多事情等着修缮
从缺乏的燃料开始
修复后
AE仍然没有足够的能量进行高速物品传输
并非使用更多电力输入
我想是时候制造中子能源元件了
这提醒了我们要解决AE频道的问题
如果这看起来很简洁
只是因为那是 p2p 网络
真正解决这个问题很难
但可以让它更易管理
在原来的控制器上搞事情会让整个基地瘫痪
所以我们应该造个新的
问题是
如果我们像这样使用无线连接器
一半的频道将被浪费
所以还是要用 p2p 通道
然而
不再是用线缆和庞大的子网来管理
我们只需要把这些频道送去一堵无线连接器墙
这是我们不佳设计的控制器的前半
（希尔伯特曲线：能填充满一个平面正方形的分形曲线，如下图所示）
还整整浪费了 900 个频道
不管怎样
我们现在有一堵漂亮的无线连接器墙可以使用了
我们要把它连到整个基地
一个一个地替换之前的 p2p
我们尽可能多的移除线缆
因为这会让游戏变卡
将所有东西重新连接到新控制器后
我们可以看看它有多乱
用电量似乎连 1A ZPM 都没有
我们甚至不需要中子能源元件
接下来，我们需要更多的电路板
看起来我们的培养缸停止生产了
不过
我们可以换成产量高 8 倍的配方
然而
这需要一种相当难以获得的细菌
用时 3 分钟成功率却仅有 7%
但是上一集已有 8 个实验室在运行
我们后顾无忧
顺便说一下
有更好的方法来复制菌群
但我们很懒
现在我们只需要建造一套新的培养缸
填充一些已有液体来启动它
完工
然而
我们还想要更快地制作电路
所以我们建了更多的装配线
幸运地
我们现在可以使用数据球复制输入总线设置
然后扩展输入子网
既然我们可以大量生产生物电路
应该斟酌各电压使用的电路板
用那个配方制作生物电路
用了相当多的无尽催化剂
库存已经告急
所以我们又做了三个太空采矿模块
并过滤要收集的物品
为了提供算力
不需要额外三台计算机
扩展一下旧的即可
通过添加网络交换机
来均分六个挖掘模块间的算力
当然还有
我们的矿石处理厂连一个采矿模块都跟不上
所以我们给它进一步超频
再堆一些机器
为了做这些材料
压模机和线缆轧机都跟不上了
但我们不用提升压模产能
隆重请出部件装配线
这将节省材料
并跳过大部分压模部分
这样做也将释放大量通用装配线的空间
那台机器看起来真的很酷
但是为了塞进单个区块
我们把它做成垂直的
但是这台机器跟不上我们的需求
所以我们超频了一点
让它和高炉的用电一样多
说到高炉
在彻底解决污染问题后
我们接着升级高炉
一旦高炉耗电比得上发电机发电
我们发现电池的容量还没激光仓的大
在获得1.6亿容量和8000核的CPU后
我们开始研究更好的电池
制作这东西需要很多时间
但与其等待
我们利用这段时间来做基建
首先，产能不够的是搅拌机
所以我们做了些共享输入样板的搅拌机阵列
我们用8仓供电
接下来
高炉由于缺乏鿫而停止工作
所以我们又造了几个物质发生器
但我们在造完后
才意识到
我们可以升压两次
或许我们应该增加更多的能源仓
下次应该做更多的测试
接下来是给电缆套皮的组装机
这台机器肯定不缺速度
它缺少的是聚苯硫醚箔
它是由我们最古老的化反被动产生的
它仍在HV电压下运行
幸运的是
附近有一条ZPM电缆
这可以让它快200倍
下一个瓶颈是琥珀金
问题是发配速度
1000个物品的缓存简直太小了
所以我们将其升级至样板输入总线
在完成置换后
便可以看到有多少材料等待处理
但现在的熔炉应该花不了多长时间就能完成任务
下一个瓶颈是卷板机
它也有同样的问题
它的输出也有问题
这是由于输出总线ME的缓存限制
而增加存储单元即可
现在它可以释放它真正的潜力了
接下来我们注意到的是晶体SoC
当时我们大量使用绿宝石配方
但现在我们可以换一个更好的
无线终端可以解决这个问题
但在修改样板后
制作进程也必须重新开始
接下来我们注意到的是
我们在电路方面没有任何进展
那是由于缺乏电路基板
在检查了我们的PCB工厂后
我们记得它没有无损超频
纳米蜂群最多能让它们工作快10倍
所以我们改变计划
重新使用大化反
但那需要很多额外的酸
它们是被动制造的
问题在于缓存的数量
所以我们增加超级缸容量
但是填充需要一些时间
由于该流体需要许多步骤
由于终极电池需要上千的HV电路板
我们可以手动批量生产不使用环氧树脂的电路板
我们马上注意到制作塑料的速度
那是一个几乎没有用过的配方
所以它被留在了旧的HV流体固化器中
感谢我们的无线通用终端
我们可以快速倍增样板
并将其移动到大固化
有了这个
我们已经完成了一批代理电路
但我们必须将它们转换为通用版本
最好不要动已有的样板
所以我们在冲压机床上增加一个存储总线
一旦我们重新查看终极电池
我们注意到激光蚀刻和切割机不工作
这是由于缺乏五级水
这里的问题是生产速度
所以我们增加了并行数
这使得机器需要更多的能量
所以我们也使用激光仓
但是我们的切割机还是不工作
于是我们动手搞了个丑陋繁琐的怪东西来帮它
我们最终完成了新电池
要使用它
我们必须把它放在盒子里
并将其放入兰波顿电容库中
那个新电容有相当大的容量
以我们目前的电力生产
填满它需要几年时间
那么我们今天学到了什么？
是呀
不要花太多时间尝试制造奇异的古代装置
它不仅不是最佳希尔伯特曲线版本